Mss.B.G61
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Articles and Notes, 1910-1966
  - Breeding records-poultry #31
  - Breeding records-poultry #32
  - Breeding records-poultry #33
  - Breeding records-poultry #34
  - Breeding records-poultry #35
  - Breeding records-poultry #36
  - Breeding records-poultry #37
  - Breeding records-poultry #38
  - Breeding records-poultry #39
  - Breeding records-poultry #40
  - Breeding records-poultry #41
  - Breeding records-poultry #42
  - Breeding records-poultry #43
  - Breeding records-poultry #44
  - Breeding records-poultry #45
  - Breeding records-poultry #46
  - Breeding records-poultry #47
  - Breeding records-poultry #48
  - Breeding records-poultry 1913 #1
  - Breeding records-poultry 1913 #2
  - Breeding records-poultry 1913 #3
  - Breeding records-poultry 1913 #4
  - Breeding records-poultry,co-operative #1
  - Breeding records-poultry,co-operative #2
  - Breeding records-poultry,co-operative #3
  - Breeding records-poultry,co-operative #4
  - Breeding records (old)-poultry #1
  - Breeding records (old)-poultry #2
  - Breeding records-rye
  - Breeding records-worksheets
  - Breeding value of individuals
  - Brief history of biological selection
  - Brief production histories of f. males
  - Calculating the sire's breeding index
  - Can artificial selection produce unlimited change?
  - Can artificial selection produce unlimited change? Third report
  - Cash value of a breeding method
  - Chances of morbid inheritance
  - Change in the physiology of the hen
  - Children of high ranking parents tend to regress to average #1
  - Children of high ranking parents tend to regress to average #2
  - Chromatin
  - Chromosome combinations in beast or fowl
  - Chromosomes and selection
  - Chromosomes, the physical mechanism of inheritance
  - Cinderella
  - Comments on "farm history"
  - Comments on the random sample tests
  - Comparison of the methods of selection
  - Comparison of progeny-test breeding of poultry with dairy cattle
  - Complete dominance charts
  - Concerning possible extension to care for the increasing demand for day old chicks
  - Concerning science
  - Concerning wheat selection
  - Continuously varying characteristics
  - Correlations are vulnerable
  - Criteria for selecting pullets for breeding
  - Cross between hollywood male and tancred females
  - Cross between two males of the victory line and females from other sources
  - Cross between two races of domestic fowl
  - Darwin's Variation of animals and plants under domestication
  - Discussion of Mount Hope breeding work, 1924
  - Disease
  - Distribution of production as an indication of fecundity
  - Doctrine of organic evolution
  - Does age of parents confer greater laying-house livability to progeny?
  - Duck descriptions, 1911-1912
  - Duck descriptions, 1913-1914
  - Early genetic station
  - Effect of gonadson soma...
  - Egg productivity in poultry
  - Egg record
  - Egg size, egg number and income
  - Entomology-orgia leucostigma
  - Essentials of genetics for those lacking fundamental biological knowledge
  - Evidence for the cumulative effect of selection
  - Experiences with colds
  - Experiment: minimum sunshine needed for normal production
  - Extra large eggs
  - Family as an index of transmitting ability
  - Family in polygenic inheritance
  - Feather pulling experiments #1, 1910-1911
  - Feather pulling experiments #2, 1910-1911
  - Filial regression and selection
  - Future of breeding
  - Genetic breeding charts
  - Genetical engineering
  - Genetics lecture, 1952
  - Genotype, phenotype, transmitting, 1933
  - Geographical distribution of species
  - Good prospects for peak production...
  - Group segregation
  - Has selection creative power?
  - Hatchability
  - Hatching quality of eggs with relation to management
  - Health control experiemnts
  - Hen feathered leghorns
  - Hen feathers text
  - Heredity of tri-color in guinea pigs #1
  - Heredity of tri-color in guinea pigs #2
  - Heredity of tri-color in guinea pigs #3
  - History of Mount Hope poultry
  - How Mount Hope learned that disease resistance could be bred into poultry
  - How much do we really know about selective breeding?
  - Human betterment by voluntary individual initiative
  - Ideas from trip to Columbus
  - Importance of continued selection
  - Improvement of the human race
  - Inbreeding
  - Inbreeding as a tool in breeding for egg production
  - Inbreeding at Mount Hope
  - Induced morphological modification in poultry
  - Influence of disease on Mount Hope flocks
  - Inheritance of schizophrenia #1
  - Inheritance of schizophrenia #2
  - Inheritance of schizophrenia #3
  - Instructions for using the family methods of breeding poultry #1
  - Instructions for using the family methods of breeding poultry #2
  - Instructions for using the family methods of breeding poultry #3
  - Is this the best method of breeding for many large eggs?
  - Kolman's Entwicklelung des menschens #1
  - Kolman's Entwicklelung des menschens #2
  - Large mice
  - Large sibships vs. small sibships
  - Lecture on egg production
  - Lecture on genetics-Williams College
  - List of experiemnts in poultry keeping...Mount Hope farm
  - Longevity short cut
  - Lerner -- Egg size and reproductive fitness
  - Lerner's reports in poultry science, California studies #1
  - Lerner's reports in poultry science, California studies #2
  - Lerner's reports in poultry science, California studies #3
  - Lerner's talk, March 8, 1954
  - Lienhart -- Biologie, de la possibilite por les eleveurs...
  - Massachusetts experiment station record forms
  - Mating--for better-for worse
  - Measuring stick
  - Medi-geno-tropic disease control
  - Method of checking transmitting ability of sires and dams
  - Method of control of the course of development of the organism by the genes
  - Method of reproducing valuable parents
  - Mice and poultry
  - Mice can help poultrymen breed better chickens
  - Mice--miscellany
  - Mice--old chapter
  - Mice (white)-weight records #1
  - Mice (white)-weight records #2
  - Mice (white)-weight records #3
  - Mice (white)-weight records #4
  - Milk production
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous notes
  - Miscellaneous notes (genetics) #1
  - Miscellaneous notes (genetics) #2
  - Miscellaneous notes (genetics) #3
  - Miscellaneous notes (genetics) #4
  - Miscellany #1, 1930
  - Miscellany #2, 1930
  - Mount Hope farm history
  - Mount Hope farm policies
  - Mount Hope farm statistics #1
  - Mount Hope farm statistics #2
  - Mount Hope history #1
  - Mount Hope history #2
  - Mount Hope history #3
  - Mount Hope philosophy of breeding
  - Mount Hope poultry flock
  - Mount Hope school of breeding
  - Mouse colony instructions, June 18, 1959
  - Multiple-factory theory
  - Multiple-factory theory (early draft)
  - Mutant genes and selection #1
  - Mutant genes and selection #2
  - Mutant genes and selection (early draft)
  - Natural selection, artificial selection and correlative variation
  - Nature of heritability
  - Nature of the gene
  - Need for more knowledge of the hen
  - Neglected possibilities in artificial selection #1
  - Neglected possibilities in artificial selection #2
  - New hen for the poultry industry
  - New knowledge of breeding--talk to poultry industry of Pennsylvania
  - Next step in breeding
  - 1943 matings
  - Normal vs. abnormal
  - Notes for a talk on breeding
  - Notes for the Lexington meeting
  - Notes-laboratory guide-outline
  - Notes--miscellaneous
  - Notes on early development of spelerpes bilineatus, green
  - Notes on frogs and toads
  - Notes on insects
  - Notes on lymplocarpus fortious and common asclepias
  - Notes-reasons for discontinuance of selective experiment
  - Notes-regression
  - Notes-technique for studying chick embryos
  - Oncoccidiosis
  - An opportunity?
  - Oregon Agricultural College #1
  - Oregon Agricultural College #2
  - Oregon Agricultural College #3
  - Origin of species
  - Outline and notes...
  - Patterns of development
  - Payne's experiments with drosophila #1
  - Payne's experiments with drosophila #2
  - Pedigree of poultry
  - Persistancy
  - Pezard's Castration alimentaire chez les coqs...
  - Piebald rats--graphs, 1914
  - Possibilities of increased egg production
  - Poultry data--miscellaneous
  - Poultry crosses relative to color
  - Poultry disease
  - Poultry disease at Mount Hope
  - Poultry management experiments
  - Poultry--Massachusetts Agricultural College, 1913-1922
  - Poultry research--Amherst, 1913-1921
    Photographs of "feminized male birds".
  - Poultry surgical operations, 1926
  - Preface
  - Prepotency records--the biological foundation
  - Preventing feather pulling and pickouts
  - Problem of sex inversion
  - Profit in crossing
  - Profit sharing hens
  - Progeny test as a means of evaluating the breeding potentialities of the individual
  - Progeny test in the sure line
  - Program of poultry matings
  - Progress in improving egg production at Mount Hope Farm
  - Progressive breeding
  - Race genetics #1
  - Race genetics #2
  - Race genetics #3
  - Race genetics #4
  - Reaction of a closed stock...to exposure to disease
  - Reasons for "50th" egg weight
  - Records and communications, 1950-1958
  - Removal and transplanting of poultry testes
  - Research methods
  - Report of N.D. Bottom's trip to palnts using battery brooders..., July 1928
  - Report of mass experiment--station flock, 1913
  - Report to Mr. Prentice from world's poultry congress, 1932
  - Research--how it should be conducted
  - Result of breeding the best of the best
  - Results of mating heterozygotes
  - Salmon blacks
  - Scientific methods
  - Selecting a herd sire, 1928
  - Selection
  - Selection and mating of domestic fowl for increased egg production
  - Selection for quality of oil in soy beans
  - Selection to selective mating
  - Selection within a pure line
  - Significance of the difference in response to selective breeding...
  - A sire's index in poultry breeding
  - Sires indices for poultry
  - Sketch of how I built in non-broodiness at M.A.C.
  - A slight difference
  - Some of the problems involved in breeding for increased egg production
  - Some phases of reproduction in domestic fowl, 1932
  - Spotting in relation to breeding problems
  - Spurs
  - Statistics...chickens
  - Statistics...chickens and eggs, 1918-1929
  - Statistics...chickens and eggs, 1929-1951
  - Statistics...chickens and eggs production
  - Story of the seven blind mice
  - Structural changes in chromosomes
  - Structure of the chromosomes #1
  - Structure of the chromosomes #2
  - Studies
  - Studies needed in genetics
  - Studies on breeding
  - Studies on Mount Hope poultry records
  - Study of fine gradations in relation to the production of much from little
  - Study of mortality in 1926-1927
  - Study of selection
  - Study of the inheritance of body weight in the albino mouse
  - Studying the inheritance of quantitative characters #1
  - Studying the inheritance of quantitative characters #2
  - Suggested methods of selective breeding
  - Suggestions for experimental work
  - Tabulating machine company #1
  - Tabulating machine company #2
  - Technic for selection for progress in quantitative characters
  - The 365 day laying period
  - The time, the source, and the manner of introducing beneficial germ plasm
  - To get high producing strain
  - Transforming black mice into white mice #1
  - Transforming black mice into white mice #2
  - Transforming black mice into white mice #3
  - Treatment of numerical equivalents of genetic formulae arithmetically
  - Trip among production poultry breeders of Massachusetts
  - Tying peoples hands
  - Ultraviolet light experiments on chicks #1
  - Ultraviolet light experiments on chicks #2
  - Ultraviolet rays
  - Unreliability of the numerical record alone as a measure of ability
  - Use of progeny records in planning matings
  - Value of progeny testing
  - Value of a quarantine method in eliminating poultry paralysis
  - Vigor
  - Weekly reports from the Mount Whitney Farm #1, 1935-1936
  - Weekly reports from the Mount Whitney Farm #2
  - What limits are there to selection?
  - White, white, white & white
    Being a statement concerning the white color occuring in mice.
  - Winter broodiness
  - Wire floors
  - Work sheets
  - Your child's birthright
  - Your child's pattern of development
- Series III. Notebooks, 1908-1913
  - Biology
  - Biology--2,3
  - The cell #1
  - The cell #2
  - Cellular biology #1
  - Cellular biology #2
  - Cellular biology #3
  - Cellular embryology
  - Chick and duck pedigree, 1908-1910
  - Chick and duck pedigree, 1911
  - Chicken pedigree, 1911-1912
  - Chicken pedigree, 1912-1913
  - Chickens
  - Chickens and ducks
  - Comparative embryology
  - Ducks
  - Experimental embryology #1
  - Experimental embryology #2
  - Fishes
  - Guinea pig code
  - Guinea pig journal
  - Hens and ducks
  - Heterocera
  - Inseta
  - Invertebrate embryology
  - Miscellaneous
  - Nervous system
  - Regeneration
  - Rotifers
  - Vertebrate animals
  - Vertebrate embryology
  - Wheeler's lectures, Physiology
  - Zoology #1
  - Zoology #2
  - Zoology #3
  - Zoology #4
  - Zoology #5
  - Zoology #6
  - Zoology #7
  - Zoology #8
  - Zoology #9
  - Zoology #10
- Series IV. Photographs, 1916-1935
  - Castrated birds, 1916-1920; Glass plates. Amherst, Massachusetts.
  - Castrated ducks, Black and white negatives.
  - Lecture slides, 1933-1935; Lantern glass slides.
  - Poultry, Black and white prints of glass slides labeled castrated birds.
- Series V. Artifacts, 1924-1926
  - Cock and hen feathers, Dec. 22 1924-Jan. 22, 1926; Feathers plucked from chickens, housed in individual envelopes.
    Mount Hope Farm Poultry Yards, Williamstown, Massachusetts.
- Series VI. Bound volumes, 1918-1956
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1918-1919; A
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1920; B
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1921-1922; C
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1922-1923; D
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1923; E
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1924-1925; F
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1925-1926; G
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets (persistency), 1926-1927; H
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1926-1927; H
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1927-1928; J
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets (second year), 1928-1929; J
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1928-1929; K
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1929-1930; L
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1930-1931; M
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1931-1932; N
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1932-1933; O
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1933-1934; P
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1934-1935; R
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1935-1936; S
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1936-1937; T
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1937-1938; U
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1938-1939; V
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1939-1940; W
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1940-1941; A
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1941-1942; B
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1942-1943
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1943-1944; D
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1944-1945; E
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1945-1946; F
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1946-1947; G
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1947-1948; H
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1948-1949; J
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1949-1950; K
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1950-1951; L
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1951-1953; M
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1952-1953; N
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1952-1953; N
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1953-1954; O
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1954; P
  - Mount Hope poultry records--family sheets, 1955-1956; R
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1923; E
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1924; F
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1923-1926; E-F-G-H
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1925-1926; G-H
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1927-1929; J-K-L
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1930-1931; M-N
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1932-1934; O-P-R
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1935-1937; S-T-U
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1938-1940; V-W-A
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1941-1943; B-C-D
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1944-1946; E-F-G
  - Mount Hope poultry records--hatching sheets, 1947-1949; H-J-K
  - Mount Hope poultry records--mating, incubator, hatching index, 1919-1920; A
  - Mount Hope poultry records--mating, incubator, hatching index, 1920-1921; B
    Mating, incubator, hatching index.
  - Mount Hope poultry records--mating, incubator, hatching index, 1921-1922; C
  - Mount Hope poultry records--mating, incubator, hatching index, 1922-1923; D
  - Mount Hope poultry records--mating sheets, 1927-1929; J-K-L
  - Mount Hope poultry records--mating sheets, 1930-1932; M-N-O
  - Mount Hope poultry records--mating sheets, 1933-1935; P-R-S
  - Mount Hope poultry records--mating sheets, 1936-1938; T-U-V
  - Mount Hope poultry records--mating sheets, 1939-1941
  - Mount Hope poultry records--mating sheets, 1942-1944